Estaba cabrona.
Si, porque no me recogiste a casa.
Y tu viendo, yo vine para acá por la mañana y me puse a hacer los platos.
Y la única razón por la cual no lo terminé fue porque el niño vino para acá y quería la leche.
Y me fue para allá para despertarme.
A que hora?
Varias veces. La mañana.
No, I had to have been there when I went outside, that I went outside to smoke for a minute and then I came again.
And he went outside and he goes,
Taba buscando.
I only used his hand.
Taba buscando, taba buscando.
He went into the room looking for you.
I must have been at that moment.
¿Dónde está Papi?
Yo, yo no sé. Está fuera.
Well, I still have to do my posting for Beckerman.
No, I did that one.
And I'm starting to work on mine.
My synthesis paper with the last one, which I'm doing on Cyber Lofi.
For do?
No, for Beckerman, so I can be done with it.
There's a posting six and then there's a, the last paper.
For Beckerman.
Which is an ethical issue in your organization.
And for do, what we have left is?
For do is the.
The project?
Yes.
There's a chat.
What day's the chat?
April 9th.
Okay.
All right.
We'll listen today at noon.
I'm going to meet Ricardo.
At the parish.
I have to take apart that pool.
Put in the new liner.
You found the liner?
I had to go to four different places and I found like.
The pinch of penny.
Over here on Bird road.
They said I had to order it.
It was special order.
They don't keep any of those things anymore.
I went to Home Depot.
The Home Depot next to where Carla works.
They didn't have it.
They didn't have even those, those liners from.
Landscape.
I went to Walmart.
They didn't have it.
I went to the other Home Depot across the street from Walmart.
And they had it and they had one and I hope it'll be big enough.
To be able to do it, but it's black.
It's a black liner.
What did you have there before?
A blue liner, a blue pool liner.
I don't think it really matters.
I don't think it's going to matter, but as long as it resists.
I've never noticed which color it is.
As long as it resists at least for tomorrow night.
That's what's important.
And so I'm hoping that that'll do all.
You didn't tell me how did it go yesterday.
Where?
At church.
Well Angulo's homily was very innocuous.
Everything went well.
I spoke to Father Frank.
He went in.
He was all nervous because we're working today together.
And he said, you know, I was reading about what had to be done.
And, and, and I go, look, I said, chill.
He goes, you've done it before.
I said, I've been doing it for 10 years.
Okay.
I said, don't worry about it.
I know how to do everything.
You concentrate on your homily.
And he goes, do you want to preach it?
I go, no, no, you're the one who's preaching.
And he goes, no, because you know, I mean, I'm preaching on Sunday already.
And I go, I'm preaching the Easter vigil.
I don't need to.
I said, that's one less thing I have to worry about.
I go, you go ahead and, and do that.
And then he was, he goes to me, oh, congratulations on your new position.
I hear you're going to be vice principal of the school.
And I told him, man, he goes, oh, you're going to be working with Sister Marisa.
Oh, she's so wonderful.
He likes her.
Yes.
He loves Sister Marisa.
She's so wonderful.
She was the vice, she was the principal at Little Flower.
When I was there teaching CCD, and she's just such a wonderful person.
And she's so nice.
And all this other stuff.
You need to bring him by when you're over.
And I told him, you know, you would have been good for the, for Father Davis's position.
Yeah.
But it was just lack of experience.
So anyway, so let's see.
And my mom says that she's going to go at three.
For the stations of the cross.
And then she's going to stay for, for the Good Friday service so that you can go at
seven and you can leave for the baby.
Oh, great.
Okay.
And what about your mom has to be there for the Easter vigil.
And Teresita wants to go because Nadine's going to be baptized there.
So.
I'm going to try to go.
And stay as long as I can.
My sister will take care of him.
He'll even sleep there.
No.
Why not?
Sleep there?
Pick him up on Sunday morning.
Well, ask her.
How's the coffee?
It's very good.
I only had, I bought French vanilla cream because that was the only one that they had
at BG.
That's fine.
I was getting kind of tired of the crumb ruler.
Okay.
I'm going to go to my school.
I need to give the tickets to the other teachers for the youth first stuff that I turned in.
And I'll take Cordeaux.
Okay.
Tell me you're leaving.
When the house is picked up.
I said, I mean, you know, tomorrow or something.
Oh, okay.
So then you can stay here, finish picking up the house.
I'll pick up just a little bit.
I'm not going to pick up the whole thing.
Okay.
I mean, Teresita's room is disgusting.
She needs to pick that up.
And David's not here.
I imagine he went to work.
I'm going to take some.
And as usual, I put it next to your side of the bed.
As usual.
Every time Easter comes that I have to do all this stuff in the parish, I get sick.
Well, Gordo's sick too.
I don't know how many times he kicked me in the bed.
No, I don't remember him kicking me.
So he must have been kicking you the whole time.
No, it was me.
It was me.
He was kicking me the whole time.
I didn't sleep very well either.
I was waking up at 3, 4, 5.
I slept pretty well.
Yeah, I know you did.
You were snoring.
And I must have slept well.
I'm quite loud, I might have.
In Gordo, was snoring.
Really loud too.
Anyway, I don't go drop that off at the motor home when I leave for the parish.
Well, de que mas quieres habar.
Yesterday the principal called me in.
She goes, I want to talk to you before I speak to that teacher.
The one that has that problem.
And I go, she goes to me, I want to speak to you before I talk to her.
Because I want the union to be okay with this.
And I go, okay.
And so I go, well, let me know what's going on.
She goes, no, I'm telling you what I'm planning to do.
Because when she comes in, she's probably going to be upset or whatever. She might come to you.
Okay.
She's coming back to work.
She came back to work.
Yeah.
You know, I was mentioning that, you know, people talk about the Catholic church and how priest,
the molest children.
Just got transferred from one place to another and the school system is doing the same thing.
But the school system is just about the same category then.
Because her dad is an attorney and her brother's an attorney.
So they're more scared of the lawsuit than they are of ethical things.
Right.
They're more scared of the lawsuit from her as an employee than the lawsuit from the parents.
Because the parents didn't do anything.
The parents that were concerned took them out, took the kids out.
That's a free program, you know?
And so, anyhow, she goes, she had come to me.
That's why I come to me a couple of days ago.
She goes, that person that you sent me an email and the resume, do you know them personally?
I go, truthfully, no.
I know her boyfriend.
I know her via email, but, you know, because we've, you know, gone back and forth and she's
in a position where she wants to...
Who's this?
A la novia de, the manager from Payway.
Oh, okay.
Right, right, right.
She was in that school.
She's in Bel Air.
She's a fifth grade, y así.
Well, that's exactly what she needs over here.
Pero, ella no quiere traer alguien.
So then tell them that they have to leave again.
No, because she's been working there less than three years.
She has to get that approved.
She, you know, it's the bureaucracy.
It takes a while.
So she goes, I need, the person that I have up there now, no da la talla.
You know?
I mean, I need to get rid of them.
And I need to bring in somebody else.
Pero with that other person, they're already in the system.
So, it's going to take a longer time.
Even though they're in the system, there's someone else who has to get approved by the
district to change.
And the principals and stuff, right?
The principal.
You remember what I went through.
And so, she goes, because I had told her, if she comes back, what we need to do is don't
put her in, don't put her in that classroom, put her in a higher grade, you know, where
kids can talk and kids can talk, you know, tell you exactly what's going on.
And so, she goes, yeah, but I think she's only certified for pre-K.
Entonces estamos, you know, stuck with her.
Entonces, she goes to me, no, but I looked up her stuff and she is K through 6, pre-K and K through
6, elementary.
I go, perfect.
And she's emotionally-
Put her with sixth grade.
Sixth grade.
No, we don't have sixth grade.
Oh, that's right.
Put her with fifth grade students.
She goes, they will eat her up.
And she'll leave.
Of course.
Eso es lo que tu quieres?
Le dije, la union me va a jodar.
Por que yo no estoy.
She goes, no, no, I do no pero es que yo le dije.
Eso es lo que tu tenias que hacer desde un principio.
She goes, si pero es que yo no sabia que ella estaba, you know, certificada
Y ella no mira los papeles y se despide de la gente.
Ella es una principal nueva. You know.
Ella esta... tu sabes. She's great, but she's new.
Ella no se sabe todavía Como access the things, or how to, you know.
She goes, she asks people, you know, the person that gave her the position or whatever and told
her, listen, look at what she's, you know, certified in.
Because that's the first thing I had asked her.
What did she certified in?
Put her somewhere else.
But I guess she hadn't really done it until she, you know, somebody told her how to do it.
Entonces, yo le dije, ahi si que no puedo decir nada porque si es una decisión administrativa.
Si a mí me cambia mañana, de first grade, a algo que yo no quiero, quinto grado como
me hizo la principal de la otra escuela, she has every right to do so.
Ahi, it's her administrative decision that I would do best in this class.
Whether I like it or not, that's, I mean, they should take that into consideration,
but they don't have to.
But at any rate, didn't they get somebody to replace her while she was gone?
They had a sub.
And so what happened when this woman came back?
Well, she requested not to have the people that, you know, made the allegations in the classroom.
And she said, look, I have no one else to put on.
So she obviously felt very uncomfortable working there.
But then that's also something that our principal told.
La principal me dijo, como ella me había dicho que no quería no estar con esta persona.
Yo le voy a decir que mira, como tu no te sientes... que piense que sea por ella.
Yo le dije, perfecto.
Así ella piensa que tu le estas haciendo un favor a ella.
Y ella no va dar la talla para eso. Por que ahi me lo dijo
Y todos esos chiquitos hablan,
Yeah.
They're emotionally, you know, disabled.
Pero le dicen hasta alma mia.
Entonces por eso la otra no podia.
ESC is really, really, really difficult.
Pero mas cuando, when you have, you know, kids that are the violent ones.
Ah, entonces, la cosa pasó que ayer, durante, ella tenía una reunión.
Like a CST, it's like a, it's a child study team.
So she was meeting with some parents and accounts or whatever.
So she wasn't in the classroom.
Y entonces, ¿quién me vino a decir eso? Dios mio.
Yo creo que fue Lily, me vino a decir, no?
Que uno de los niños de la clase, de ahí, de ella, lo encontraron en la calle descalzo.
Running through the street.
Entonces, figúrate.
La principal le cayó a ello.
Pero ¿qué pasó?
Entonces, la principal fue adentro de la clase.
Eh, que, you know, to find out what happened.
How could this child just walk out?
Entonces habían dejado, había, there was like an electric cord that didn't keep the door from closing all the way.
The child snuck out.
But this is from your school?
Yeah.
From her class.
Where are you going?
Okay, hurry up because I don't want you to leave your brother out there alone.
And the child snuck out.
So she, the principal went in there to try to see how could this happen.
And happened to prevent it from happening again.
Porque dice que, the person that, two people that found it, you know, figurate that it's around the park, people walk around, you know.
So they found these, este, un niñito chiquitico, sin zapato, because it was nap time, eh, corriendo por ahí.
Entonces, they brought him back.
Dice que el señor was a Vietnam veteran.
Y dice que estaba hasta llorando, porque dice que le recordó a los niños en Vietnam, you know, running with the bombs and stuff, and barefoot.
Y, you know, dice que estaba, you know, he was really traumatized with the whole thing.
Figura tener loco horrible in school.
Entonces, she goes, she goes, oh, I went in there.
I was talking to the Aids.
Y tú sabes dónde estaba la doña?
I know she was in a meeting during that time.
She goes, yeah, that's her classroom.
Ella estaba recogiendo como si no fuera nada con ella.
Entonces, si es tu clase donde algo que pasó con tu estudiante, tú no vas a estar ahí presente para que no ocurre de nuevo.
Y esta es la misma que fue acusada.
Sí.
So she doesn't give a damn about the kids.
No, she doesn't.
Of course she doesn't.
Y esta no es la primera vez que la ha caído esto arriba en otra escuela.
Yo la había dicho, eventualmente ella se va a ir, pero le va a tirar ese problema a otra persona.
Ahora la cosa es que in Fifth Grade, EFC, ella está en el building de nosotros,
donde ella puede estar constantemente vigilando y tiene personas al lado.
Y ella seguro que le va a decir a las maestras al lado que sean bien vigilantes, ¿no?
Y además de eso, ella puede estar constantemente chequeándole, porque ella es un desastre.
She doesn't have plans.
She doesn't have, you know, she comes up with things al último minuto.
Ella no toma eso en serio.
Pero yo le dije, perfecto.
Eso es lo perfecto, porque eso es exactamente lo que yo le había dicho a la principal, desde un principio.
Le había dicho, tenemos que meterla en una clase para acá, donde podemos estar.
Y ustedes, tú sabes, caminar, you know, en la clase, lo que sea.
Entonces yo le dije, oye, la unión no va a votar, no va a votar para carajo.
Just, you know, because sinceramente, la unión es secundario.
Para mí lo primero.
Es lo niño.
Absolutely.
Y además, eso es lo que dice el contrato.
To the primary purpose of the educators, is the student.
So I'm going by the contract.
Pero además, ella no está haciendo nada.
Claro, las dos sabemos que lo que queremos es que se vaya para carajo.
Pero ahí sí que puede ella documentar porque ahí ella sí que tiene que tener las cosas bien organizadas.
I think Christie is going to start in our school in June.
She already resigned?
Well, I don't know.
She's resigned.
She hasn't signed the contract yet.
She has resigned.
But I think they started calling people down to sign the contracts on Thursday.
I mean, not Thursday once.
Yesterday.
Yesterday was Wednesday.
Yeah, yesterday.
No, yesterday was Thursday.
No, Wednesday.
I'm sorry.
They started calling people down.
So I imagine that they'll be calling her soon to go sign her contract.
And then the nun said that to see if she could be coming in.
You know, at some point.
Maybe for like a week or something just to see how things are.
And then probably start in June to try and get the...
Yo sé que Stephanie really wants to, you know, work there or whatever.
It might be better for her not to.
For you and for her.
¿Por qué?
¿Qué pasa con las cosas de Ocarito? Te vienen a ti.
¿Qué va a pasar con las cosas de ella?
They're going to come to me.
Right?
So...
No, mi papá me lo dijo.
Mi papá me lo dijo.
Me dijo, mira, alegra, hasta que no le den trabajo a David.
Y esta chiquita, bueno, ya está ahí.
No, David.
Uh.
A David lo vamos a votar en devaluar un lugar.
Si no se cuida.
What I told her is get your certification.
Exactly.
In social studies so that you can work at a public school.
And then she told me, no, Luis was saying that in Ferguson there's going to be openings for six new teachers in every department.
And I go, well, there's your entry right there.
Exactly.
You know?
There's always openings in there.
And she said, yeah, but you know, I don't want to work in public school.
And I go, well, you know what?
If you work in a public school stuff and you're going to make more money than what I'm making right now.
Okay?
And I said, so go ahead and start doing that.
And the only way you're going to get fired is if you do something to one of the kids.
Yes.
Unless you have during the first 30 days or first day, they have the option to, you know, if they see that you're really bad, they can throw you out with the first 30 days.
Cuando estabamos en la clase el Sabado that Mancibo was talking about that, there was a teacher that they had, you know, done a whole bunch of things I know exactly what they were talking about from, you know, from the school I was at before.
And I go, did you get hired somewhere else?
Y esa maestra, no hacia nada. Se sentaba en la clase, tu sabe que a comer, y organizar la cartera. Eh, entonces le pregunto a los muchachos,
Are you sick?
And if they were sick and they were out, they were asking, what did you have?
Oh, no, I, you know, I had, you know, stomach virus. Oh, stomach virus. Okay.
She would come back and say, you know, she's sick and she would ask for workers' compensation because she got the stomach virus from a kid in the class.
How do people like that get jobs?
Esperate, that's not the worst. Y se robaba cosas. Yo la vi going through my desk.
Well, that's the one that you caught going through your desk over here?
No, not here.
At the other one?
Right, right, right, right. Y ya me lo habia dicho mi hermana, me lo había dicho varias personas, cuidado, no dejes nada de valor porque esta se los lleva.
That's just amazing to me.
Because it takes, you have to document those things for a long time.
That's the thing with, that's the thing with my school, since we work on contract, you break your contract, you're out.
They have to hear, they give you the opportunity, they put you on an improvement plan, and if you don't improve, then it takes a long time.
You know, we try to help you out.
We'll put a mentor, we'll give you ideas, we'll talk to you, but if it doesn't improve, you're out.
You're out.
I wish I would do that with the kids.
Because the parents, in essence, sign a contract with the kids when they get there, which is the handbook.
You break that, you should be out.
I don't know, but the kids continue to go, you know, I'm just, I don't know, it really bothers me.
I'm looking for a rough year next year, I'm telling you, it's going to be rough.
I have the teachers on one side expecting me to do everything, I have, I don't know.
Invita a Father Frank, algunas de las celebraciones, y dicelo a sisters, porque si el le gusta a ella, y tu sabe, se cain bien.
Yeah, I'll tell her, bueno, not her, I got to tell sister words.
Para el año que viene, you know, to put him on schedule to go and celebrate Mass.
Right.
Because Father Dave is just to bring people all the time, but that was him, but now Father Eastern is going to be doing the same thing, so.
I'm hungry. Tu no tienes hambre?
I'm still having coffee.
I already had my coffee.
I'm hungry.
Ve a buscar algo.
I just have like a wicked day.
Pero bueno, estamos connectados. I guess we could hop in the car with it and go get it.
It's portable.
You want to?
You just hop in the car and go get some pastelitos?
No.
Yeah, he could be babysitting.
He's outside right now.
I mean, apparently he's keeping the kids entertained.
And my cyber loafing paper, I have six pages.
It has to be 10.
I don't know what I'm going to do with that paper.
I have no idea.
What ethical, come on, you must have done something.
What ethical dilemma do I have in my place of business?
Let me see.
I hate my boss.
I think she's a hypocrite.
My ethical dilemma, the fact that I'm choosing to work with her closer now in my new position.
That's my ethical dilemma.
I don't know how I'm going to work with her.
Isn't there something you've done in St. Thomas about ethics? Porque esta señora no,
Even though that's what the guidelines say,
Tu sabes que ella te da full credit for just doing it.
She hasn't given me back my grade on the presentation.
And it really bothers me that Richard got the same thing that I did.
How do you know?
You don't know this?
Everybody was saying it.
Everybody got a 20 on their presentation.
I mean, come on, my presentation was a hell of a lot better than a lot of other people's there.
Yes, but...
I got my grade the day after, and I posted my thing during class.
I sent her my thing on Monday, the day right after class,
and it's Friday today, and she still hasn't posted my grade.
Then you send her an email, Dr. Brackerman?
I just wanted to confirm that you did receive my...
She did. She sent me an email that she received it.
Oh, okay.
Were you able to open it all right, um, you know?